<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-03-14T04:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Choosing the Ironyard</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2014/03/14/choosing-the-ironyard.html"/>
    <id>/blog/2014/03/14/choosing-the-ironyard.html</id>
    <published>2014-03-14T04:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-14T04:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So. About my first post. After a reread, I realized I’d fallen into some old habits. As a writer, I distance myself. I get vague. I avoid specifics and details. I guess at its core, this is a form of hiding. And it reveals the great paradox of writing...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So. About my first post. After a reread, I realized I&amp;rsquo;d fallen into some old habits. As a writer, I distance myself. I get vague. I avoid specifics and details. I guess at its core, this is a form of hiding. And it reveals the great paradox of writing for me. I want to be known; it&amp;rsquo;s why I write. There&amp;rsquo;s part of me that wants to connect. But another part of me is terrified of being exposed in this way—even if I&amp;rsquo;m the one initiating the exposure. But these days, I&amp;rsquo;m all about doing things differently. That means that it&amp;rsquo;s time for specifics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why the Iron Yard?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to say I chose The Iron Yard after extensive research and forethought. And I suppose that, in one sense, I did. I&amp;rsquo;ve made a hobby of reading about dev bootcamps—from Dev BootCamp in San Francisco to Bitmaker Labs in Toronto to CodeFellows in Seattle to the Nashville Software School. I mean, I was a licensed lurker. So I guess you could say I knew the lay of the land. But when it came to actually choosing The Iron Yard, I made the decision to apply about two minutes after I found The Iron Yard&amp;rsquo;s website. There were basically two crucial factors in making that choice. First, The Iron Yard was opening a coding academy in Atlanta. I could attend without having to pay for a place to stay. That meant I could almost afford to do it:) Second, The Iron Yard offers a guarantee: a job within six months or your money back. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to have a partner in the boat with you, partcularly if you&amp;rsquo;re setting out for parts unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yeah, I read more about The Iron Yard before actually applying, enough to put myself at ease with the idea of taking this leap. But the truth is that I was ready to jump—and the Iron Yard seemed like a soft landing spot:) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to delve deeper in my next post, including taking a look at what scares me about the road ahead. So, more specifics.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
