<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-03-20T04:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>The Fear&amp;#58; Changing Careers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2014/03/20/the-fear-changing-careers.html"/>
    <id>/blog/2014/03/20/the-fear-changing-careers.html</id>
    <published>2014-03-20T04:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-20T04:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p class="first"&gt;
So, I’m afraid. I wish I wasn’t, but there it is. I’m at the precipice now, the jumping off point. &lt;a href="http://theironyard.com/academy/rails-engineering/"&gt;Rails bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; starts in under two weeks. Several times lately, I’ve been reminded: the mind can be a trap. I keep thinking about all of the decisions...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p class='first'&gt;
So, I&amp;rsquo;m afraid. I wish I wasn&amp;rsquo;t, but there it is. I&amp;rsquo;m at the precipice now, the jumping off point. &lt;a href="http://theironyard.com/academy/rails-engineering/"&gt;Rails bootcamp&lt;/a&gt; starts in under two weeks. Several times lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reminded: the mind can be a trap. I keep thinking about all of the decisions that led me here; I can&amp;rsquo;t change them, but part of me desperately wishes I could—just a few of them, really. What if I&amp;rsquo;d made this decision five years ago, ten years ago? My life would be set, right? What if I&amp;rsquo;d been smarter, stronger, and better all along? And yeah, that&amp;rsquo;s the fear (and doubt) talking. Because I&amp;rsquo;m actually pumped about the road ahead. I want to go to dev bootcamp. I want to learn Rails (and more!). I want to spend more time coding.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s going on here? What am I afraid of? And yes, I&amp;rsquo;m going to do my best to be &lt;a href="/choosing-the-iron-yard"&gt;very specific&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the first time in a long time, I&amp;rsquo;m afraid of tomorrow. It&amp;rsquo;s uncertain. It&amp;rsquo;s unmapped. I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing the same thing for more than ten years. I&amp;rsquo;m a creature of habits. Change is scary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m afraid of the upset this could cause my family. I&amp;rsquo;m a new dad. My amazing daughter is eight months old. My wife is awesome—and so supportive. And I know the road I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen is going to mean new difficulties for them. Yes, I hope to build a better future for all of us, but I worry about the challenges my family will face in the present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m afraid of the test. Am I good enough? Smart enough? Can I face the things I&amp;rsquo;m not good at—public speaking, taking criticism, whatever parts of coding I happen to be particularly horrible at, etcetera? There are moments when I know that &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; is the answer to all of these questions, when I know I can face the test ahead, but the self-doubt is never far away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m afraid of being broke. That&amp;rsquo;s all I&amp;rsquo;ll say about that:)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this is an incomplete list, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ve hit the highlights of my own personal mind trap. The key, I guess, is not getting stuck in that trap—and getting out when you are stuck. Because I suspect that the fears themselves aren&amp;rsquo;t the problem; the problem is going round and round in the accompanying anxiety. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;rsquo;s where I&amp;rsquo;m at. Trying not to get stuck. Trying not to fixate. And though I don&amp;rsquo;t have any miracle fixes figured out, I&amp;rsquo;ve been running across a nice formulation on twitter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;fun == hard returns true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More and more, I think this is one of the secrets of life that I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to learn. Hard (and scary) ain&amp;rsquo;t the end of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Choosing the Ironyard</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2014/03/14/choosing-the-ironyard.html"/>
    <id>/blog/2014/03/14/choosing-the-ironyard.html</id>
    <published>2014-03-14T04:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-03-14T04:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So. About my first post. After a reread, I realized I’d fallen into some old habits. As a writer, I distance myself. I get vague. I avoid specifics and details. I guess at its core, this is a form of hiding. And it reveals the great paradox of writing...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So. About my first post. After a reread, I realized I&amp;rsquo;d fallen into some old habits. As a writer, I distance myself. I get vague. I avoid specifics and details. I guess at its core, this is a form of hiding. And it reveals the great paradox of writing for me. I want to be known; it&amp;rsquo;s why I write. There&amp;rsquo;s part of me that wants to connect. But another part of me is terrified of being exposed in this way—even if I&amp;rsquo;m the one initiating the exposure. But these days, I&amp;rsquo;m all about doing things differently. That means that it&amp;rsquo;s time for specifics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why the Iron Yard?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to say I chose The Iron Yard after extensive research and forethought. And I suppose that, in one sense, I did. I&amp;rsquo;ve made a hobby of reading about dev bootcamps—from Dev BootCamp in San Francisco to Bitmaker Labs in Toronto to CodeFellows in Seattle to the Nashville Software School. I mean, I was a licensed lurker. So I guess you could say I knew the lay of the land. But when it came to actually choosing The Iron Yard, I made the decision to apply about two minutes after I found The Iron Yard&amp;rsquo;s website. There were basically two crucial factors in making that choice. First, The Iron Yard was opening a coding academy in Atlanta. I could attend without having to pay for a place to stay. That meant I could almost afford to do it:) Second, The Iron Yard offers a guarantee: a job within six months or your money back. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to have a partner in the boat with you, partcularly if you&amp;rsquo;re setting out for parts unknown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yeah, I read more about The Iron Yard before actually applying, enough to put myself at ease with the idea of taking this leap. But the truth is that I was ready to jump—and the Iron Yard seemed like a soft landing spot:) &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to delve deeper in my next post, including taking a look at what scares me about the road ahead. So, more specifics.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
